# Salvador Arrazola

### Software Developer

#### **PROFILE**

Hello! My name is Salvador, I'm a software developer with more than 10 years of experience in analyzing and developing desktop and web applications, mainly with Java and React. I have experience in designing and creating relational and non-relational databases, developing, and supporting monolithic, event-oriented and microservices applications, as well as cloud-based applications.

I like to work in environments with Agile methodologies, enjoy teamwork, sharing knowledge, solving issues and innovating. I'm fascinated by the software development cycle and I greatly enjoy the interaction with the client from problem setting and requirements to the release of the system or features. I've experience working with distributed teams globally. My English level is sufficient, and I speak a little of French.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Backend Developer - Java | Fullstack Developer - Java & React | Business Analyst | Database Architect | Cloud Computing

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Fullstack Developer - Java & React

2020 - 2022 | IBM

- Supported and improved Global Accounting apps integrated in the global IBM sellers support platform called Engage Support.
- These apps were developed using event-drive and microservices architectures, and using React, Java Spring framework (Java 8), relational plus non-relational databases and deployed over OpenShift cloud platform through DevSecOps pipelines.
- Participated in cloning, testing, and training efforts for duplicating Global Accounting apps in Engage Support system for new company Kyndryl after IBM company split in 2020.
- Worked on an Agile environment, focused on client satisfaction and continuous improvement.

### **Entrepreneur Partner**

### 2017 - 2019 | Autonomous

- Started some family business: bottled water refilling, cleaning products store and independent real estate advisory.
- As part of this experience, I improved a lot my soft skills: time management, stay focus, client relationship and negotiation, selling speech, effective communication, among others.
- I was also able to apply my IT and software development knowledge to improve efficiency in each one of these businesses.

### Business Analyst & Developer - VBA

### 2014 - 2016 | HP & HPE

- Led split and clone process to duplicate my department apps during HP company split in 2015.
- Improved and implemented some automations for logistics and supply chain processes.
- Responsible for managing Windows virtual servers, MSQL Server databases and IIS web services.
- Developed and supported a traveling budgets and expenses app for Global Logistics team all around the world
- Automated some daily-basis processes: data repositories, Excel and SAP macros, email alerts, reports, among others.
- Maintained and improved an inventory adjustments application for HPE Warehouse in Guadalajara.
- Developed and supported a system for tracking shipments for ELF Program (Embedded Logistics Freight) at global level.

### Contractor Developer at HP - VBA

#### 2013 - 2014 | Sinergia

- Responsible for supporting and improving the following Microsoft VBA based tools:
- + NPI Tracker: Allow users to track tasks status for new product introduction process, for Latin and North American regions.
- + Description Maker: Generate product descriptions according to HP official naming rules, to feed different business systems.
- + UID Tracker: Allow users to track tasks status for releasing CTO (Configure To Order) products in Latin America and Brazil.

**4**%

Guadalajara, Mexico

 $\bowtie$ 

salvador.arrazola@gmail.com

in

<u>salvador-arrazola</u> <u>salvador-arrazola</u>

<u>Satisfactor arra</u>

### **EDUCATION**

### Computing Enginery | Bachelor's Degree

2003 – 2007 | University of Guadalajara

Software Systems Orientation.

## Web Development | Sun Microsystems Cert. 2006 | University of Guadalajara

Web Component Development with Servlets& JSP Technologies.

**English | ISE 1 - Trinity College Certification** 2006 - 2007 | Proulex

### Java Certification | SCJP 5.0 Certification 2010 | Sun Microsystems

 Sun Microsystems Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform SE 5.0.

### Web Development

### 2011 | Proulex Computing

• Internet Programming Training (PHP, Java EE, Ruby).

## Web Development | IBM Training & Badges 2020 - 2022 | IBM

 Carbon Design System with React, Security and Privacy by Design Foundations, Agile Explorer, Cognitive Practitioner, Docker Essentials, Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner.

### **TECH SKILLS**

- DevSecOps
- Version Control
- Coding Proficiency
- Clean Code & SOLID
- Unit Testing & TDD
- Java 8 & Java Spring
- Apache Kafka
- JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3
- React
- IBM Carbon System Design

- Relational & No Relational DBs
- Cloud Computing
- Kubernetes
- Red Hat OpenShift
- Excel MacrosVisual Basic
- C# & .Net
- SAP Macros
- Windows ServerAdministration

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Agile Principles & Ceremonies
- Effective
- Communication
- Team Collaboration
- Feedback Believer
- Continuous & Self Learning
- Stay Focus & Time Management
- Logic & Critical Thinking
- Empathy
- Decision Maker
- Proactiveness
- Problem Solving

### ERP Developer - VBA & Java

2007 - 2012 | Pixvs - University of Guadalajara

- Implemented and supported Intuitive ERP in some regional manufacturing companies, using Microsoft VBA, .NET and MSQL Server.
- Generated a developing model to create a Java and SQL desktop-based ERP named Pixvs.
- Led a team for developing, implementing, supporting, and customizing Pixvs ERP in enterprises of Corporate Business at University of Guadalajara (Proulex, Black Lions Soccer Team, Gas Stations, Telmex Auditorium, FIL).
- Developed and supported an administration system (SIARH) for Human Resources Coordination at University of Guadalajara. This system was based in Pixvs ERP.

### **Independent Programming Instructor**

2007 - 2011 | University of Guadalajara

• Participated as independent instructor of programming languages like Java SE, Java EE, Java ME, JavaScript, Ajax, PHP, and C, at the Users Training Unit in the Systems Information Coordination.

### **Software Development Intern**

2006 - 2007 | University of Guadalajara

- N1 Grid Engine Intern: Assisted in managing computer clusters at the High-Performance Computing Center
- Java Technologies Intern: Participated as developer in the Behavior's Studies and Research Center, coding experiments using Med State Notation (a states programming language from Med Associates company). Created a web application using PHP to publish digital media for researchers of the Academic Center of Economic and Management Sciences.

#### Systems Dept. Assistant

2000 - 2002 | Walmart Supercenter

 Participated in configuring and maintaining computer equipment, generating sales, purchase and inventory reports, and managing the store merchandise systems.

### **TOOLING**

- Jira & Trello
- Mural & Draw.io
- Office
- Travis, UCD, New Relic & Sonarqube
- GitHub
- Docker

- VS Code, IntelliJ &
- Netbeans
- DBeaver
- MSQL & MySQL
- IBM Cloudant
- PostgreSQL

### **HOBBIES**

- Anime series
- Sci-Fi novels, movies & series
- Videogames
- Reading